Gary McKeever

Software Developer

Greater Duluth Area, MN 218 290 6677

gmckeever88@outlook.com https://garymckeever.us

Languages

C#

SQL

TypeScript

JS/HTML/CSS

Python

PHP

C++

Technologies

.NET/core

Node.js

Angular

Electron

WPF

LINQ

NoSQL

ML.NET

Azure Cloud Compute

Strengths

Full stack development

Relational databases

Responsive design

Data analysis

web/desktop development

OOP

MVVM

Machine learning in .NET

REST API use and development

Soft Skills

Problem solving

Embraces change

Resourceful

Bright attitude!

Creative

Efficient

Root cause analysis

Articulate communicator

Forward thinking

Comfortable facing clients

Cut, clean, and organized

Operates in uncertainty easily

Education

2015 - 2017

BS, Computer Science | UMD

2015 - 2017

Minor, Business Admin | UMD

2007 - 2010

AA | MRTC

References are available upon request.

Summary

Software developer with a diversified skill set going on 5 years of experience. Has a knack for creative problem solving and quickly learning new frameworks and environments. Looking for an opportunity for rapid professional development and career growth.

Experience

Since 2016, I have been professionally creating software to manage business (ERP), visualize finance and operational data, and solve any other cases that arise. I also work on personal projects in my spare time – some to help me grow as a developer, some just for fun!

Professional

- Business Management ERP (C#, .NET, SQL Server)
 - A full stack, solo written, custom web app that includes project management, time tracking, purchasing, and payroll.
 - My current employer uses this system to run day to day business for ~50 staff.
- Cashboard (C#, WPF, SQL Server, DevExpress)
 - o An operations and finance analytics desktop app, much like Tableau.
 - Data is compiled and cleaned through SQL scheduler/custom console app and visualized in pivot grids and charting.
- SAGE 100 Integrations (Sage VI, Sage ODBC Data Provider)
 - Business system and Cashboard utilize custom integrations to SAGE for data entry and analysis.
 - Cashboard's data compiler normalizes SAGE's backend for trend analysis.
- ArcGIS Client Portal (Sequelize, Express.js, Angular, Node.js, ArcGIS.js)
 - o A premise hosted client accessible web app that visualizes spatial data through ArcGIS.js SDK.
 - o Collaborated with NorthPoint GIS in a team environment.

Personal

- RaspiBot (Python, Raspberry Pi B+, motors, servos, camera + US sensors)
 - Robot that utilizes onboard sensors to track and follow input colors.
 - Uses camera and US sensors for obstacle avoidance.
- Vexlus (ASPNET Core, Angular, Nebular UI, SQL Server, Azure CosmosDB, Azure Cloud Services, Azure DevOps Pipelines)
 - A text analysis web app that uses NER and a custom relation solution to map unstructured text into a graph.
 - o Identifies relationship patterns in text to discover links between entities.
 - Built off of a scalable multi-tenant capable code base.
- https://garymckeever.us (GitHub pages, MDB, JS/CSS/HTML)
 - Personal development, resume, and home page.
 - Single page and simple design allow for easy nav and edit.

Employment History

November 2016 - Present

Software Developer, NTS

- Maintain existing company software by debugging, testing, and adding feature requests.
- Create software to visualize and interpret data generated by company applications.
- Design understandable UI/UX for company staff and clients.

January 2015 – May 2017

Pharmacy Technician | Inventory Manager, CVS Pharmacy

November 2011 - January 2015

Pharmacy Technician | Team Member, Target